<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Peng Liu</title>
    <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Peng Liu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 Peng Liu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>J. C. Berry, M. Qi, B. V. Sonawane, A. Sheflin, A. B. Cousins, J. Prenni, D. P. Schachtman, P. Liu, R. S. Bart (2022), Increased signal to noise ratios within experimental field trials by regressing spatially distributed soil properties as principal components, eLife 11:e70056.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/elife2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/elife2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. Qi, J. C. Berry, K. Veley, L. O’Connor, O. M. Finkel, I. Salas-González, M. Kuhs, J. Jupe, E. Holcomb, T.G. del Rio, C. Creech, P. Liu, S. Tringe, J. L. Dangl, D. Schachtman, R. S. Bart (2022), Identification of beneficial and detrimental bacteria impacting sorghum responses to drought using multi-scale and multi-system microbiome comparisons, ISME J.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/isme2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/isme2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. I. Natukundaa, M. B. Mantilla-Pereza,b, M. A. Grahama,c, P. Liu, and M. G. Salas-Fernandez (2022), Dissection of canopy layer-specific genetic control of leaf angle in Sorghum bicolor by RNA sequencing, BMC Genomics, 23, 95.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R. Bi and P. Liu (2021), A Semi-parametric Bayesian Approach for Detection of Gene Expression Heterosis with RNA-Seq Data, Journal of Applied Statistics, 2021, DOI:.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jas2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jas2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. Goren, C. Wang, Z. He, A. Sheflin, D. Chiniquy, J. Prenni, S. Tringe, D. Schachtman, P. Liu*, Feature selection and causal analysis for microbiome studies in the presence of confounding using standardization. BMC Bioinformatics 22, 362 (2021)</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. Goren, C. Wang, Z. He, A. Sheflin, D. Chiniquy, J. Prenni, S. Tringe, D. Schachtman, P. Liu*, Feature selection and causal analysis for microbiome studies in the presence of confounding using standardization. BMC Bioinformatics 22, 362 (2021)</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. Goren, C. Wang, Z. He, A. Sheflin, D. Chiniquy, J. Prenni, S. Tringe, D. Schachtman, P. Liu*, Feature selection and causal analysis for microbiome studies in the presence of confounding using standardization. BMC Bioinformatics 22, 362 (2021)</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2024/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J. Zhao, Y. Qi, P. Liu, A. Severin, M. Sayadi, I. Paetau-Robinson, W.S. White, (2021). Prebiotic Effects of a Cranberry Beverage in a Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, Crossover Clinical Trial. Current Developments in Nutrition, 5(2), 1190.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/nutrition2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/nutrition2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P. Kanodia, V. Paramasivan, R. Srivastava, R. Bi, P. Liu, W. A. Miller, S. H. Howell (2020), Control of translation during the unfolded protein response in maize seedlings: Life without PERKs, Plant Direct.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantdirect2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantdirect2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J. Bao, Y. Yu, H. Li, J. Hawks, G. Szatkowski, B. Dade, H. Wang, P. Liu, T. Brutnell, B. Spehar, N. Tye-Murray (2020), Evidence for Independent Peripheral and Central Age-Related Hearing Impairment, Journal of Neuroscience Research.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jnr2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jnr2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L. A. Laboissonniere, J. J. Goetz, G. M. Martin, R. Bi, T. J.S. Lund, L. Ellson, M. R. Lynch, B. Mooney, H. Wickham, A. Mani, P. Liu, G. W. Schwartz, and J. M. Trimarchi (2019), Molecular signatures of retinal ganglion cells revealed through single cell profiling, Scientific Reports.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/scientificreports2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/scientificreports2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L. Dong, L. Qin, X.Dai, Z. Ding, R. Bi, P. Liu, Y. Chen, T. Brutnell, X. Wang, and P. Li (2019) Transcriptomic Analysis of Leaf Sheath Maturation in Maize, International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20(10), 2472.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/ijms2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/ijms2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. He, K. Wimalanathan, P. Liu, C.J. Lawrence-Dill (2019), Compare Expression Profiles for Pre-defined Gene Groups with C-REx. Journal of Open Source Software, 4(37), 1255.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/joss2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/joss2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A. Sheflin, D. Chiniquy, C. Yuan, E. Goren, I. Kumar, M. Braud, T. Brutnell, A. Eveland, S. Tringe, P. Liu, S. Kresovich, E. Marsh, D. Schachtman, and J. Prenni (2019), Metabolomics of sorghum roots during nitrogen stress reveals compromised metabolic capacity for defense response, Plant Direct.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantdirect2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantdirect2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R. Bi, P. Liu, R Package ssizeRNA: Sample Size Calculation for RNA-Seq Experimental Design</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rssizerna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rssizerna/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. Goren, P. Liu, R Package BinQuasi: Analyzing Replicated ChIP Sequencing Data Using Quasi-Likelihood</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rbinquasi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rbinquasi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R. Srivastava, Z. Li, G. Russo, J. Tang, R. Bi, U. Muppirala, S. Chudalayandi, A. Severin, M. He, S. Vaitkevicius, C. Lawrence-Dill, P. Liu, A.E. Stapleton, D. Bassham, F. Brandizzi, and S. Howell (2018). Persistent ER stress in maize seedlings engages ZmIRE1 in a multiphasic process that transitions from prosurvival activities to cell death. Accepted by The Plant Cell.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantcell2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantcell2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y. Zhang, R. Giuliani, Y. Zhang, W. L. Araujo, B. Wang, P. Liu, Q. Sun, A. Cousins, G. Edwards, A. Fernie, A. Barkan, T. Brutnell, and P. Li (2018). Characterization of maize leaf Pyurvate Orthophosphate Dikinase using high throughput sequencing. Accepted by the Journal of Integrative Plant Biology.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jipb2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jipb2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. Goren, P. Liu*, C. Wang, and C. Wang (2018). BinQuasi: a peak detection method for ChIP-sequencing data with biological replicates. Bioinformatics.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. He, P. Liu, and C.J. Lawrence-Dill (2017). A hypothesis-driven approach assessing significance of differences in RNA expression levels among specific groups of genes. Current Plant Biology, 11–12 (2017), pp. 46-51.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/cpb2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/cpb2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C. Zhang, S. Fei, P. Liu, T. Ji, J. Peng, U. Frei, and D. Hannapel (2017). Transcriptome changes in response to cold acclimation in perennial ryegrass as revealed by a cross-species microarray analysis. Crop Science, 57(Suppl1):S-179-S-191.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/cropsci2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/cropsci2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L. Laboissonniere, G.  M. Martin, J. J Goetz, R. Bi, B. Pope, K. Weinand, L. Ellson, D. Fru, M. Lee, A. K Wester, P. Liu, and J. M Trimarchi (2017). Single cell transcriptome profiling of developing chick retinal cells. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 2017 Aug 15; 525(12): 2735-2781.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jcn2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jcn2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S. Hu, C. Wang, D. Sanchez, A. Lipka, P. Liu, Y. Yin, M. Blanco, and T. Lubberstedt (2017). Gibberellins promote brassinosteroids action and both increase heterosis for plant height in maize (Zea mays L.). Frontiers in Plant Science, 8:1039.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/frontiers2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/frontiers2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N. Cray, Y. Zhao, Y. Fang, P. Liu, L. Pollak, S. Duvick, D. F. Birt, and E. M. Whitley (2017), Effects of dietary resistant starch on the WNT signaling pathway and preneoplastic cells in the colons of azoxymethane-treated rats. Nutrition and Cancer, 69(4):632-642.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/nutritioncancer2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/nutritioncancer2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H. Sun, P. Liu, L. Nolan, and S. Lamont (2016). Thymus Transcriptome Reveals Novel Pathways in Response to Avian Pathogenic Escherichia coli (APEC) Infection. Poultry Science, 95(12): 2803-2814.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/poultrysci2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/poultrysci2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z. Ding, Y. Zhang, Y. Xiao, F. Liu, M. Wang, X. Zhu, P. Liu, Qi Sun, W. Wang, M. Peng, T. Brutnell, and P. Li (2016). Transcriptome response of cassava leaves under natural shade. Scientific Reports, 6:31673.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/scireports2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/scireports2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B. Nelson, N. Cray, Y. Ai, Y. Fang, P. Liu, E. M. Whitley, and D. Birt (2016). Effect of Dietary Resistant Starch on Inhibition of Colonic Preneoplasia and Wnt Signaling in Azoxymethane-Induced Rodent Models. Nutrition and Cancer, 68(6):1052-63.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/nutritioncancer2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/nutritioncancer2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F. Liu, C. Wang, Z. Wu, Q. Zhang, and P. Liu* (2016). A Zero-Inflated Poisson Model for Insertion Tolerance Analysis of Genes Based on Tn-seq Data. Bioinformatics, 32(11): 1701-1708.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H. Sun, R. Bi, P. Liu, L. Nolan, and S. Lamont (2016). Combined Analysis of Primary Lymphoid Tissues&#39; Transcriptomic Response to Extra-intestinal Escherichia coli (ExPEC) Infection. Developmental and Comparative Immunology, 57:99-106.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/dci2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/dci2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R. Bi, and P. Liu* (2016). Sample size calculation for designing RNA-sequencing experiments. BMC Bioinformatics, 17:146.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcbioinformatics2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcbioinformatics2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F. Liu, C. Wang,  and P. Liu* (2015). A Semi-parametric Bayesian Approach for Differential Expression Analysis of RNA-seq Data. Journal of Agricultural, Biological, and Environmental Statistics, 20(4):555-576.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jabes2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jabes2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H. Sun, P. Liu, L. Nolan, and S. Lamont (2015). Novel Pathways Revealed in Bursa of Fabricius Transcriptome in Response to Extraintestinal Pathogenic Escherichia coli (ExPEC) Infection. PLoS ONE, 10(11):e0142570.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H. Sun, P. Liu, L. Nolan, and S. Lamont (2015). Avian pathogenic Escherichia coli (APEC) infection alters the bone marrow transcriptome in chickens. BMC Genomics, 16:690.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2015_sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2015_sun/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J. E. Koltes, E. Fritz-Waters, C. J. Eisley, I. Choi, H. Bao, A. Kommadath, N. V. L. Serão, N. J. Boddicker, S. M. Abrams, M. Schroyen, H. Loyd, C. K. Tuggle, G. S. Plastow, L. Guan, P. Stothard, J. K. Lunney, P. Liu, S. Carpenter, R. R. R. Rowland, J. C. M. Dekkers, and J. M. Reecy (2015). Identification of a putative quantitative trait nucleotide in guanylate binding protein 5 for host response to PRRS virus infection. BMC Genomics, 16:412.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2015_koltes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2015_koltes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. Orr, P. Liu, R Package ssize.fdr: Sample Size Calculations for Microarray Experiments</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rssize_fdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rssize_fdr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. Orr, P. Liu, and D. Nettleton (2014). An Improved Method for Computing Q-values when the Distribution of Effect Sizes is Asymmetric. Bioinformatics, 30(21):3044-3053.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2014_orr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2014_orr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L. Wang, A. Czedik-Eysenberg, R. A. Mertz, Y. Si, T. Tohge, A. Nunes-Nesi, S. Arrivault, L. K. Dedow, D. W. Bryant, W. Zhou, J. Xu, S. Weissmann, A. Studer, P. Li, C. Zhang, T. LaRue, Y. Shao, Z. Ding, Q. Sun, R. V. Patel, R. Turgeon, X. Zhu, N. J. Provart, T. C. Mockler, A. R. Fernie, M. Stitt, P. Liu, T. P. Brutnell (2014). Comparative analyses of C₄ and C₃ photosynthesis in developing leaves of maize and rice. Nature Biotechnology, 32(11):1158-1165.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/naturebiotech2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/naturebiotech2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T. Ji, P. Liu, and D. Nettleton (2014). Estimation and Testing of Gene Expression Heterosis. Journal of Agricultural, Biological, and Environmental Statistics, 19(3):319-337.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jabes2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jabes2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y. Du, C. Wang, and P. Liu (2014). A Permutation Test of Genetic Association between Salmonella Isolated On-farm and At-abattoir using Amplified Fragment Length Polymorphism. Journal of Biometrics and Biostatistics, 5:204.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jbb2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jbb2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S. L. Taustra, P. Li, Y. Si, N. Gandotra, P. Liu, Q. Sun, T. P. Brutnell, and T. Nelson (2014). Developmental dynamics of Kranz cell transcriptional specificity in maize leaf reveals early onset of C4-related processes. Journal of Experimental Botany, 65(13):3543-3555.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jeb2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jeb2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y. Si, P. Liu*, P. Li, and T. Brutnell (2014). Model-based clustering of RNA-seq data. Bioinformatics, 30(2):197-205.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2014_si/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2014_si/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W. Landau, and P. Liu (2013). Dispersion Estimation and Its Effect on Test Performance in RNA-seq Data Analysis: A Simulation-Based Comparison of Methods. PLoS ONE, 8(12):e81415.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2013_landau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2013_landau/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z. Wu, O. Sahin, Z. Shen, P. Liu, W. G. Miller, and Q. Zhang (2013). Multi-omics approaches to deciphering a hypervirulent strain of Campylobacter jejuni. Genome Biology and Evolution, 5(11):2217-2230.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/gbe2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/gbe2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y. Si, and P. Liu* (2013). An Optimal Test with Maximum Average Power While Controlling FDR with Application to RNA-seq Data. Biometrics, 69:594-605.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/biometrics2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/biometrics2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q. Xia, W. T. Muraola, Z. Shen, O. Sahin, H. Wang, Z. Wu, P. Liu, and Q. Zhang (2013). Adaptive mechanisms of Campylobacter jejuni to erythromycin treatment. BMC Microbiology, 13:133.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcmicrobiology2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcmicrobiology2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H. Hao, Z. Yuan, Z. Shen, J. Han, O. Sahin, P. Liu, and Q. Zhang (2013). Mutational and transcriptomic changes involved in the development of macrolide resistance in Campylobacter jejuni. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 57(3):1369-1378.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/aac2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/aac2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X. Chen, P. Liu, and H-H. Chou (2013). Whole-genome thermodynamic analysis reduces siRNA off-target effects. PLoS ONE 8(3):e58326.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2013_chen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2013_chen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. E. Sandford, M. Orr, X. Li, H. Zhou, T. J. Johnson, S. Kariyawasam, P. Liu, L. K. Nolan, and S. J. Lamont (2012). Strong Concordance Between Transcriptomic Patterns of Spleen and Peripheral Blood Leukocytes in Response to Avian Pathogenic Escherichia coli Infection. Avian Diseases, 56(4):732-736.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/aviandiseases2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/aviandiseases2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H. Lin, C. Wang, P. Liu, and D.J. Holtkamp (2012). Construction of Disease Risk Scoring Systems using Logistic Group Lasso: Application to Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome Survey Data. Journal of Applied Statistics, 40(4):736-746.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jas2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jas2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y. Si, P. Liu, R Package MBCluster.Seq: Model-Based Clustering for RNA-seq Data</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rmbcluster_seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rmbcluster_seq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. Orr, P. Liu, and D. Nettleton (2012). Estimating the Number of Genes that are Differentially Expressed in Both of Two Independent Experiments. The Journal of Agricultural, Biological, and Environmental Statistics. 17(4):583-600.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jabes2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jabes2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y. Si, P. Liu, R Package AMAP.Seq: Compare Gene Expressions from 2-Treatment RNA-Seq Experiments</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/ramap_seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/ramap_seq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W. Fang, Y. Si, S. Douglass, D. Casero, S. Merchant, M. Pellegrini, I. Ladunga, P. Liu, and M. Spalding (2012). Transcriptome-Wide Changes in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii Gene Expression Regulated by Carbon Dioxide and the CO2-Concentrating Mechanism Regulator CIA5/CCM1. The Plant Cell, 24(5):1876-1893.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantcell2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantcell2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P. Liu*, and C. Wang (2012). Robust Semiparametric Optimal Testing Procedure for Multiple Normal Means. Journal of Probability and Statistics, Volume 2012, Article ID 913560.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jps2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jps2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T. Ji, P. Liu, and D. Nettleton (2012). Borrowing Information Across Genes and Experiments for Improved Error Variance Estimation in Microarray Data Analysis. Statistical Applications in Genetics and Molecular Biology, 11(3): Article 12.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/sagmb2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/sagmb2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T. Luangtongkum, Z. Shen, V. W. Seng, O. Sahin, B. Jeon, P. Liu, and Q. Zhang (2012). Impaired fitness and transmission of macrolide-resistant Campylobacter jejuni in its natural host. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 56(3):1300-1308.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/aac2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/aac2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. E. Sandford, M. Orr, M. Shelby, X. Li, H. Zhou, T. J. Johnson, S. Kariyawasam, P. Liu, L. K. Nolan, and S. J. Lamont (2012). Leukocyte Transcriptome from Chickens Infected with Avian Pathogenic Escherichia coli Identifies Pathways Associated with Resistance. Results in Immunology, 2:44-53.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/resultsimmunology2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/resultsimmunology2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P. Liu, and Y. Si (2014), Book Chapter: Cluster Analysis of RNA-sequencing Data, in the book of Statistical Analysis of Next Generation Sequencing Data</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bookchpt2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bookchpt2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P. Liu, and Y. Si (2014), Book Chapter: Cluster Analysis of RNA-sequencing Data, in the book of Statistical Analysis of Next Generation Sequencing Data</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bookchpt2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bookchpt2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V. M. Kvam, P. Liu*, and Y. Si (2012). A comparison of statistical methods for detecting differentially expressed genes from RNA-seq data. American Journal of Botany, 99(2):248-256.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/ajb2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/ajb2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L. Wang, Y. Si, L. K. Dedow, Y. Shao, P. Liu, and T. Brutnell (2011). A Low-Cost Library Construction Protocol and Data Analysis Pipeline for Illumina-Based Strand-Specific Multiplex RNA-Seq. PLoS ONE, 6(10):e26426.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plosone2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. E. Sandford, M. Orr, E. Balfanz, N. Bowerman, X. Li, H. Zhou, T. J. Johnson, S. Kariyawasam, P. Liu, L. K. Nolan, and S. J. Lamont (2011). Spleen transcriptome response to infection with avian pathogenic Escherichia coli in broiler chickens. BMC genomics, 12:469.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G. Li, K. Tivendale, P. Liu, Y. Feng, Y. Wannemuheler，W.Cai, P. Mangiamele, T. Johnson, C. Constantinidou, C. Penn, and L.K. Nolan (2011). Transcriptome Analysis of Avian Pathogenic Escherichia coli O1 in Chicken Serum Reveals Adaptive Responses to Systemic Infection. Infection and Immunity, 79(5):1951-1960.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/infectionimmunity2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/infectionimmunity2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X. Yu, L. Li, J. Zola, M. Aluru, H. Ye, A. Foudree, H. Guo, S. Anderson, S. Aluru, P. Liu, S. Rodermel, and Y. Yin (2011). A brassinosteroid transcriptional network revealed by genome-wide identification of bes1 target genes in Arabidopsis thaliana. The Plant Journal, 65(4):634-646.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantj2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantj2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P. Li, L. Ponnala, N. Gandotra, L. Wang, Y. Si, L. Tausta, T. Kebrom, N. Provart, R. Patel, C.R. Myers, E.J. Reidel, R. Turgeon, P. Liu, Q. Sun, T. Nelson, and T. Brutnell (2010). The developmental dynamics of the maize leaf transcriptome. Nature Genetics, 42(12):1060-1067.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/naturegenetics2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/naturegenetics2010/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J. T. G. Hwang, and P. Liu (2010). Optimal tests shrinking both means and variances applicable to microarray data analysis. Statistical Applications in Genetics and Molecular Biology, 9(1): Article 36.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/sagmb2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/sagmb2010/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. Orr, and P. Liu* (2009). Sample size estimation while controlling false discovery rate for microarray experiments using the ssize.fdr package. The R Journal, 1(1): 47-53.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rjournal2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/rjournal2009/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S. Covshoff, W. Majeran, P. Liu, J. M. Kolkman, K. J. van Wijk, and T. Brutnell (2008). Deregulation of maize C4 photosynthetic development in a mesophyll cell-defective mutant. Plant Physiology, 146:1469-1481.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantphysiology2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/plantphysiology2008/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X. Zheng, H-C Huang, W. Li, P. Liu, Q-Z Li, and Y. Liu (2007). Modeling nonlinearity in dilution design microarray data. Bioinformatics, 23(11):1339-1347.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2007_zheng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2007_zheng/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P. Liu*, and J. T. G. Hwang (2007). Quick estimation of sample size while controlling false discovery rate and application to microarray analysis. Bioinformatics, 23(6):739-746.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2007_liu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bioinformatics2007_liu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R. J. H. Sawers, P. Liu, K. Anufrikova, Q. Sun, G. Olsefski, J. T. G. Hwang, and T. Brutnell (2007). A multi-treatment experimental system to examine photosynthetic differentiation in the maize leaf. BMC genomics, 8:12.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/bmcgenomics2007/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S. A. Jesch, P. Liu, X. Zhao, M. T. Wells, and S. A. Henry (2006). Multiple Endoplasmic Reticulum-to-Nucleus Signaling Pathways Coordinate Phospholipid Metabolism with Gene Expression by Distinct Mechanisms. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 281:24070-24083.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jbc2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/jbc2006/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N.-S. Tan, N. Shaw, N. Vinckenbosch, P. Liu, R. Yasmin, B. Desvergne, W. Wahli, and N. Noy (2002). Selective cooperation between fatty acid binding proteins and peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors in regulating transcription. Molecular and Cellular Biology, 22(14): 5114-5127.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/mcb2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/mcb2002/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J. Ni, P. Liu, and H. Jia (2000). Binding Properties of M-CAT Element in the Chicken Nicotinic Acetylcholine Receptor γ-Subunit Promoter. Chinese Journal of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, 16(5):580-585.</title>
      <link>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/cjbmb2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pliu.rbind.io/publication/cjbmb2000/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>